<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">adam wheeler</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2016-03-03T00:02:15-08:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Adam Wheeler</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>adamwheeler88@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekend Trip to Yosemite]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/Yosemite/" />
  <id>/Yosemite</id>
  <updated>2016-03-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-03-02T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Adam Wheeler</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>adamwheeler88@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;h2&gt;Yosemite National Park 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently two more college friends have transplanted into the Bay Area for work: one in tech in the City, and another in nursing. Even though I’m meeting some great people and making all kinds of new friends here in the Bay, it’s been really nice having some fellow Texan transplants. They make me feel a little bit more at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past weekend another one of our mutual friends flew into the Bay due to a ridiculously affordable round trip ticket from Southwest ($100 round trip!), and asked if I wanted to go camping in Yosemite. If you read my &lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Goals&quot;&gt;Personal Goals&lt;/a&gt; post, you’ll know that I’ve been wanting to travel a lot more this year, so I jumped at the opportunity to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Texas, I had never really seen actual mountains; the closest thing I’ve ever really seen was the hill country in Austin. As we drove into the Sierras, I was amazed by the sheer size of everything I was seeing. We drove past a sign that said we were about 6,000 feet in elevation; over a mile above the Bay Area! This was also my first time driving on winding mountain roads, and seeing that there weren’t many guard rails around was pretty intense…not to mention going around blind corners/hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got into the park (for free thanks to JR being an American Hero with his active military ID), we made our first stop at the Bridalveil Falls. We decided to hike in toward the falls, despite a sign warning that the area is dangerous. The rocks were pretty slippery, but the views were well worth the careful trek up toward the falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bridalveil Falls; Slippery &lt;strike&gt;When Wet&lt;/strike&gt; All the Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0516.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0516.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridalveil Falls&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0514.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0514.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridalveil Panoramic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some lunch and eventually got a camp spot in Park 4, an area where you just setup a tent where you can find some open ground. With our tent pitched, sleeping bags unpacked and set up, Camp Booger was broken in with an inagural 30 minute nap before hitting the trails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_5326.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Images/Yosemite/IMG_5326.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nap time in the Yosemite Valley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we woke up, 2 hours later, we decided to hike the Mirror Lake trail before the sun went down to get a nice view of Half Dome. When the water on the lake is calm and not moving, you can see a perfect reflection of Half Dome on the surface. Unfortunately, the water was moving pretty quickly on our visit, and Mirror Lake wasn’t so mirrory. No worries though, because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Half Dome Didn&#39;t Disappoint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You really should view these photos on a big screen to appreciate the beauty of it! These photos were taken with my iPhone 6S, and I was very pleased with the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/half-dome-pano.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Images/Yosemite/half-dome-pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Panoramic of Half Dome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/halfdome.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Images/Yosemite/halfdome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset on Half Dome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got some amazing shots while at Mirror Lake, at just took a while to soak in the scene. These photos don’t do the majesty and sheer size of the area justice; you really have to go experience it all for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0528.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/IMG_0528.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_0536.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/IMG_0536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/IMG_5461.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/IMG_5461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Texans in the Bay!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/SAM_2552.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/SAM_2552.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/SAM_2593.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/SAM_2593.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Group Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://adamw88.github.io/Images/Yosemite/SAM_2612.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/yosemite/SAM_2612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Another Group Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Yosemite 2016&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Yosemite/&quot;&gt;Weekend Trip to Yosemite&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Adam Wheeler at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;adam wheeler&lt;/a&gt; on March 02, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Personal Goals for 2016]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/Goals/" />
  <id>/Goals</id>
  <updated>2016-03-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-02-19T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Adam Wheeler</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>adamwheeler88@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This year I really want to focus on my own personal and professional growth. I’ve always said that as soon as you feel comfortable in your professional life, you stop growing and its time to do/learn something more. My good friend and life coach/professional mentor, Jide, taught me that in your professional life, its all about the value you bring to the table. If you ever stop increasing your value, you’re only harming yourself and someone else is working longer, harder, more efficiently than you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the people who will ultimately be successful, and you’ll wonder ‘why don’t I have that?’.Over the last 3 years, I’ve come to realize how absolutely true that statement is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of things that I want to do this year. These aren’t New Year’s Resolutions, because everyone makes those and then forgets about them. I want to do everything on this list for the betterment of myself, my future, and for the sake of always learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My goals for 2016 are:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a website to force myself to document my work/life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn Python, Java, and whatever else seems like a natural progression.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beef up my Github and contribute to open source projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put a hardware project on Kickstarter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend a Hack-a-thon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get back into shape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vlog&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be an all around better person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address most of the above, I’ve pretty much submersed myself in MOOCs through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edx.org&quot;&gt;edX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://udemy.com&quot;&gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coursera.com&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Udemy is the worst of the three. Most of their courses are not free, and the special bundles that they have are often for courses that are several years old containing outdated content with lots of deprecated functions and syntax. I appreciate the quality and quantity of their courses, but I’m not about dropping $50+ on something I can find on Google for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently taking a CompSci course from MIT and a power electronics series from University of Colorado on edx that are both really great, and are available for free. The courses I’m taking all have video lectures complete with subtitles, homework/quizzes/tests, discussion boards, progress page with all of your grades, and direct lines of communication to TAs if you ever need/want help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more and more I learn about software, the more interested I am in it. Being able to immediately see the results of your work, unlike hardware design, is very satisfying. I intend on keeping up with my MOOC courses to learn more about software engineering and fun challenge sites like HackerRank. Who knows, maybe even end up with a software position sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning about pretty much whatever you can think of, head over there and give them a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.github.com/adamw88&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot;&gt;My Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Goals/&quot;&gt;Personal Goals for 2016&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Adam Wheeler at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;adam wheeler&lt;/a&gt; on February 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello world]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/first-post/" />
  <id>/first-post</id>
  <updated>2016-02-11T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Adam Wheeler</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>adamwheeler88@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I really want to begin documenting my life, goals, work, and memories through YouTube and blogging. I’ve been wanting to make a tech blog for quite some time, but never really made a conscious effort to. 
That, or I would try to pick up web development, read a bit into something like Ruby on Rails, get lost, and stop caring or get busy doing something else. 
This blog is my attempt to rectify that, and what better a place to do it than Github pages?! I can host my
own site, store my code/PCBs with version control, and &lt;em&gt;pay absolutely nothing&lt;/em&gt; all in one place? Its the perfect solution to my needs, and Jekyll is a joy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an electrical engineer and techie at heart. I love designing hardware and PCBs, and dabbling in software to bring things to life. I am always trying to learn something new to build cool hardware and software applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My areas of interest, and thus the focus of this blog, are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hardware/electronics design engineering
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Power electronics&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Embedded systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PCB design&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Low voltage systems&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hacks with Arduino/Raspberry Pi&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software engineering
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Interfacing with hardware&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data science&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorials (with Github!!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration (start ups etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whatever I feel like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, a little bit about myself. I’m an electrical engineer in the San Francisco Bay Area working for Tesla Motors. Having moved recently, I’m loving life out in the Bay.
The weather is a significant improvement over Texas, and the fact that I can go hiking, surfing, AND skiing in the same day blows my mind. Public transportation that is actually 
worth a damn is a revelation in my life. The views are unlike anything I’ve ever seen, and to be able to walk around in Facebook/Google/Apple headquarters is awesome and inspiring. 
There’s an entrepreneurial energy here that is definitely absent from Houston. It feels like if you have an idea, you can find people to help you work on it and maybe make it come
to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say the Bay Area isn’t without its faults. Here are a few things that I’ve noticed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rent is outrageous. Seriously, a piece of shit in San Francisco is at least $2300. You wonder why everywhere here makes &amp;gt;$100,000? Its because of the cost of living.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a car if you’re in the city or Oakland is an expensive pain, and parking is a nightmare. If you’re lucky enough to have a complex that comes with a parking spot, you’ll pay between $100-300/mo for it, or you’re gonna have to find street parking. Speaking of parking…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The San Francisco Municipal Transportation Agency is evil. Deciphering the plethora of signage in some areas of the city is unnecessarily complicated. Coming from a city that never had street sweeping, it is a huge pain. Where I am in Oakland, the streets are offset so that streets in one direction only allow parking Mon/Weds/Fri and the perpendicular streets are Tues/Thurs with street sweeping between the hours of 3-5am. What this means is if you don’t have a parking spot, you need to move your car every single day to a different spot, or be ticket $66.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State tax. Enough said.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I’m really liking this huge change in my life. California is ‘hella’ cool.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/first-post/&quot;&gt;hello world&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Adam Wheeler at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;adam wheeler&lt;/a&gt; on February 11, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
